<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0" 
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-1.0.0.xsd">
	<body>
		<release version="1.50" date="" description="Major refactorings">
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T22:01:26">
				Check Client examples
				<fixes issue="39" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T15:43:40">
				INDINumberElement in Client library should check the values in the [min, max] range
				<fixes issue="38" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:18">
				Integrate Astronomy Control Center into de library
				<fixes issue="36" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:15">
				updateProperty does not throw an exception anymore
				<fixes issue="31" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:24">
				slf4j introduced for better logging
				<fixes issue="30" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:22">
				Maven folder renaming
				<fixes issue="29" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:14">
				Driver extensions
				<fixes issue="28" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:27">
				Event handler directly attached to the properties
				<fixes issue="27" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:23">
				Annotations for easy property definitions
				<fixes issue="26" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:32">
				Move every abstract driver to it's own Maven Module
				<fixes issue="25" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:33">
				Package renaming: laazotea.indi.xxx -> org.indilib.i4j.xxx
				<fixes issue="24" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:16">
				Generics in INDIProperty
				<fixes issue="23" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:26">
				Base directory for all I4J stuff
				<fixes issue="22" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:25">
				Use Logger framework
				<fixes issue="18" />
			</action>
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:34">
				Replace org.indilib.i4j.Base64 with apache commons-codec
				<fixes issue="12" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:12">
				Update existing drivers to new changes
				<fixes issue="11" />
			</action>
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:35">
				Check old tutorials and examples
				<fixes issue="10" />
			</action>
			<action dev="zerjillo" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:29">
				Extract Client examples to their own Maven Module
				<fixes issue="9" />
			</action>
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:28">
				Check documentation of every method/class
				<fixes issue="8" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:19">
				Use Maven Code Formatting Plugin
				<fixes issue="7" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:20">
				Use Maven License Plugin
				<fixes issue="6" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:21">
				Remove CCD stuff that should be handled at client level
				<fixes issue="5" />
			</action>
			<action dev="ritchie_gmx_at" type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:13">
				Getting maven-release to work with central
				<fixes issue="3" />
			</action>
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:30">
				Avoid some API exposures
				<fixes issue="2" />
			</action>
			<action type="update" system="SourceForge2" date="2014-10-14T09:03:31">
				Element iterators in properties
				<fixes issue="1" />
			</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.38" date="July 22, 2014">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Base Library: Solved a bug in SexagesimalFormatter that treated some negative numbers as positive (thanks to Romain Fafet for pointing this
				out).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Base Library: Added a INDIDate class that helps handling dates for the future Telescope Drivers (thanks to Gerrit Viola).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client Library: In INDINumberElement the setValue(String valueS) does not currently throw the IllegalArgumentException when an incorrect value
				is passed (less han minimum or greater than maximum) as it seems that some not very well
				implemented drivers (QHY5 one, for example) might send incorrect values when the deviced
				are not initialized (thus breaking some clients). This should be later examined for a better solution if that drivers are not corrected.
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver Library: The INDIFocuserDriver can get updates about the speed from the device.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.37" date="January 11, 2014">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Sky Quality Meter - LU Driver: Initial release of the driver</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver Library: Some method renaming.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Raspberry Pi GPIO Driver: One element in the System Info Group was repeated.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.36" date="November 23, 2013">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client Library: Important bug corrected when creating Properties and Elements. I still don't know how it has previously worked :-P</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">ClientUI Library: Some cosmetic changes for Properties with multiple Elements.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">ClientUI Library: Added a new control for Switch Properties with One of Many rules (based on a combo box).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Added convenience INDIOneElementXXXProperty classes for properties with only one element.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Raspberry Pi GPIO Driver: Added this driver to control the GPIO ports of the Raspberry Pi.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.35" date="November 12, 2013">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Seletek Driver: Corrected the "model" property for focusers. Now it has the "DC" option.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Seletek Driver: Added a third port for the Platypus model.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Seletek Driver: Added some power settings for focusers.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">QHY Filter Wheel Driver: The port property now is stored in the server.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver Library: Added a convenience method "setValues" to INDIProperty to avoid dealing with elementsAndValues arrays in many typical
				situations.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver Library: Corrected a bug that allowed to add new elements to initialized properties.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.34" date="November 10, 2013">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">QHY Filter Wheel Driver: Small bug corrected: now the filter slots are not read when filter names change.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">QHY Filter Wheel Driver: Added some documentation about the Filter Wheel.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Class INDISwitchOneOfManyProperty class created to easily manage One Of Many Switches (no Switch elements direct dealing).
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Class INDISwitchOneOrNoneProperty class created to easily manage One or None Switches (aka one simple button).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Fixed bug about the default value in the INDIPortProperty</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: INDINotLoadableDriver is now an Interface (it was an error design to make it as a subclass)</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Added the mechanism to register and unregister subdrivers</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Important bug corrected in INDIPortProperty that prevented changes to its value</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: INDIFocuserDriver class added to create focuser drivers</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver Library: Improved the mechanism to save / load properties to files: the Property classes have some factories that may be used to create
				auto - saveable properties. In addition, when using those factories it automatically loads the
				properties if they exist. Otherwise they are created with the standard
				constructor.
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server Library: Small changes to avoid loading INDINotLoadableDriver s</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Seletek Driver: Added this driver to control focusers based on the Seletek by Lunatico (http://lunatico.es)</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.33" date="October 6, 2013">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Updates to the class INDIFilterWheelDriver to adjust to the standard properties in the INDI protocol.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">QHY Filter Wheel Driver: Updated driver to conform the new INDIFilterWheelDriver and added the posibility to configure the wheel (specify
				filter positions).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Minimal corrections.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.32" date="July 25, 2013">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">AndroidUI library: Some refactoring. The Application and Activity classes are moved to the examples package.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">AndroidUI library: "Better" looking Views</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">AndroidUI library: Some icons added.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">AndroidUI library: Now application can change orientation without reseting interface.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">AndroidUI library: Tabs can be removed dinamically. So we handle device removals and disconnections.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library: Avoid some null pointer excetion in disconnect() in INDIServerConnection (fatal for Android).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library: Added some convenience methods to retrieve Properties by group name in INDIDevice and all Properties in an INDIDevice.
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library: Added some convenience methods to get the value of a property as a String.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library: Important bug fixed: listeners could not be notified if some of them were removed while notifying</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library: Added the getValueAsString() method to INDIElement s</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Basic Server has an added "r" command to reload all jarFiles (very useful for testing).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: The servers avoid directly loading the INDINotLoadableDriver s</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Several changes to be able to deal with drivers with subdrivers (unloading and reloading Java drivers not working properly if
				subdrivers exist).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added a method to get the standard Connection property if the driver implements INDIConnectionHandler and fixed some minor
				errors regarding the Connection property.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added the class INDINotLoadableDriver to create drivers that should not be directly loaded by a Server.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Several changes to be able to deal with drivers with subdrivers.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added methods to serialize and deserialaze properties to disk. This allow to save properties and values in different
				executions of the driver.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added the class INDIPortProperty to ease dealing with the standard INDI DEVICE_PORT Property.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added a convenience method to turn just one switch element ON and the rest OFF.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added the class INDIFilterWheelDriver for easier development of Filter Wheel drivers.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">QHY Filter Wheel Driver: Added this new driver</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.31" date="April 12, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Now the Server handles correctly the enableBLOB policies.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Added some abstract methods in AbstractINDIServer to be able to handle new connections and broken connections with Clients and
				detecting when drivers are disconnected / stopped.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library: Added functionality to allow the server to stop listening to new connections and to break all current Client connections.
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Basic library: Addition of BLOBEnables to Constants</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library: INDIDevice refactored to better implement the enableBLOB messages.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library: INDIDeviceListener refactored to avoid ugly hacks with Strings.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.30" date="April 9, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Added the Android Client UI library: It allows to create ugly but functional Android Clients.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: The updateProperty() method in INDIDriver throws a INDIException in case of error (not previously added to the Driver or
				Switch Property not following its rule).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Changed the calls to Arrays.copyOf to be compatible with Android 8.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Changed the padLeft function in INDISexagesimalFormatter to be compatible with Android 8.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.21" date="April 4, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">General changes:String.isEmpty() replaced by String.length() == 0. Android Java version does not allow the isEmpty() method.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">General changes: Change the Project names to better accomodate the INDI for Java name. JAR files also renamed.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library: UI classes moved to a different library. This refactoring is done to avoid problems with Android apps (Android does not
				support Swing). The methods "getDefaultUIPanel()" are changed to "getDefaultUIComponent()" that use
				reflection in order to obtain the best suited UI component (depending on the
				included UI libraries).
			</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library: Added method isStarted() in INDIDriver to know if the Driver has started listening.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Server library: Basic server moved to examples package.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Server library: Some small refactoring to allow to load INDI for Java Drivers that are already in the classpath (via the loadJavaDriver(Class
				cls)) method.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Server library: Some functionality of the BasicServer has been moved into a DefaultINDIServer. The INDIServer class has been renamed to
				AbstractINDIServer.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Server library: Added the method acceptClient(Socket) to AbstractINDIServer to allow the filtering of clients based on their Inet address.
			</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.20" date="April 2, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Server library available!: We have a new library to develop INDI Servers. A basic server has been added that alows to dinamically load and
				unload INDI for Java Drivers, Native Drivers and Network Drivers (other Servers).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library changes: Properties return the Elements of their correspondign type (easier coding).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library changes: UI for properties refactored to be able to create new Panels for properties.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library changes: New UI for standard CONNECTION property.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Client library changes: Corrected a bug that made the status of properties be BUSY if the answer of the Driver is very fast.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library changes: Added a waitForDevice() methos in INDIServerConnection (similar to the waitForProperty method in INDIDevice).</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Client library changes: Added a waitForDevice() and waitForProperty() methods with a maximum wait time.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">General INDI library changes: Added isValidXXX() functions for PropertyStates, LightState, SwitchStatus, PropertyPermission and SwitchRule in
				Constants.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library changes: Removed unnecesary disconnect() method in INDIDriver.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">General INDI library changes: Added isValidXXX() functions for PropertyStates, LightState, SwitchStatus, PropertyPermission and SwitchRule in
				Constants.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">General INDI library changes: Added XMLToString class.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">General INDI library changes: Refactored the socket reading functions in all the driver, client and server libraries.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.11" date="March 26, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library: INDIElements must specify its owner Property. Thus, it is not necessary to add them to the property. At the time of its
				construction they are added to the property.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library: INDISwitchElement ensure that the other elements are not selected if their owning Property has a rule of ONE_OF_MANY or
				AT_MOST_ONE and the new value is ON.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library: The generic CONNECTION property is handled via the new INDIConnectionHandler interface. The Drivers will automatically add and
				handle the property if the Driver implements the interface.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Driver library: Added a printMessage method to allow the easy printing of messages in the Server console.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">Driver library: Fixed a major bug that avoided the correct removal of properties when INDIDriver.removeProperty(...) was called.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">General library: Added a INDIException from which all specific exceptions will inherit</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.10" date="March 19, 2012">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Added the Driver Library. Now it is possible to create INDI Drivers!</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">A lots of refactoring in the INDI Client.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Added a generic Library with the classes shared by the Clients and Drivers.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="update">The update Properties method for the Client has been improved. Now it is simpler to ask the Driver to change some Property values.</action>
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">The complete directories of each one of the three libraries is released (source code, Netbeans project, Java Docs and dist files).</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.01" date="March 06, 2012" description="JApplet INDI Client example">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add"> Added a new JApplet INDI Client example application.</action>
		</release>
		<release version="1.00" date="March 06, 2012" description="Initial Version of the Library">
			<action dev="Zerjillo" type="add">Initial Version of the Library (just the Client).</action>
		</release>
	</body>
</document>
